# Stephen D. Moreira

Software Engineer

### **Personal Info**

#### **Address**

406 Pointe Allyson Way Orlando, Florida 32825

#### Phone

407-310-8747

#### E-mail

smoreira1@live.com

#### GitHub

https://github.com/smoreira1

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenm oreira/

# **Full-Stack**

**Front-End** 

Advanced

**Back-End** 

**Proficient** 

**Database** 

Advanced

#### **Soft Skills**

**Team Player** 

Advanced

**Team Lead** 

**Proficient** 

Independent Worker

**Expert** 

**Innovator** 

Advanced

**Work Ethic** 

Expert

Excited Full-Stack Software Engineer with 6+ years experience developing applications from academic oriented projects to high-volume and high-complexity business solutions. An enthusiastic team player passionate about progressive web applications. Adapts well to culturally diverse work environments, with a willingness to engage in new challenges and innovations.

# **Experience**

Jun 2017 -

present

#### **Software Engineer**

Lockheed Martin UKMFTS Team

- Developed in Java/J2EE for UKMFTS sustainment team, worked bugs listed in JIRA task manager and reported progress on fixes and development during scrum meetings followed by code commits to a SVN on completed and reviewed tasks.
- Exported application database schemas such as tables, indexes, constraints, sequences, views and procedures into DDL scripts for a clean database instance.
- Configured **JBoss** and **Tomcat** applications, deploying new code to test webservers as well as creating and running acceptance test procedures for new software patches.
- Developed for Internet Explorer 7 / Internet Explorer compatibility mode using vanilla JavaScript techniques as well as utilizing Internet Explorer specific Document Object Model behaviors.

Feb 2016 -Jun 2017

## **Programmer Analyst Lead**

Lockheed Martin ShareSpace Team

- Researched, incorporated and taught AngularJS Framework into software team's development life cycle.
- Established problem specifications and system designs by working closely with customers and translating complex technical concepts.
- Maintained and monitored database and web servers to ensure high availability using Enterprise Manager and SQL Developer applications.
- Led weekly and daily software meetings to communicate priorities and distribute workloads.
- Updated back-end data by inter-communicating between AngularJS factories and PL/SQL packages returning JSON to front end interface.
- Mentored junior software developers in best practices; such as, applying table indexes, SQL tuning and SQL data-binding ensuring top performance and security.
- Spearheaded team in developing the A.L.I.S checklist. A single page application using AngularJS, PHP, IIS and Oracle with responsive components and design such as BootStrap3 and JQuery Datatables.
- Independently designed, developed and deployed stockroom application using AngularJS, PHP, and PL/SQL, consistently following up with end-users for application improvements and additional requirement changes.
- Reduced cross site scripting security issues by 70% by revamping projects to AngularJS and teaching developers about AngularJS sanitation and databinding concepts.
- Reduced overall ShareSpace application complexity by introducing AngularJS's Model-View-Controller, separation of concerns and reactive programming concepts.
- Created Gulp task runner to minify JavaScript and CSS files improving pages loads up to 30%.

Mar 2015 - **Programmer Analyst** 

Feb 2016 Lockheed Martin ShareSpace Team

# **Technologies Angular2+** Learning **AngularJS Expert Angular Material** Advanced **Bootstrap3 Expert** CSS3 **Proficient** HTML5 **Expert JQuery Expert** Java **Proficient JavaScript** Advanced Node.js **Proficient** PHP **Proficient Protractor Proficient** Polymer 2.0 Learning SQL & PL/SQL Advanced **XML** Advanced

- Converted HTML5 tables to JQuery DataTables across several applications
  utilizing extension libraries for easy export to Excel, PDF and CSV as well as
  native table searching, pagination and sorting.
- Designed and developed transactional and analytical data structures importing from a HANA database into a local Oracle database via materialized views and database links.
- Eliminated 100% of SQL injection security issues by porting PHP data logic from back-end application to PL/SQL stored procedures and packages using data-binding.
- Created **micro-services** and a **RESTful** api for receiving department tracking application, increasing page loads by 300%.
- Designed and developed operations excellence teams meeting tool using PHP,
   P.E.A.R, PL/SQL and JQuery using AJAX calls for asynchronous design.
   Allowing teams to track actions, attendance, generating statistics and notifications based on actions and attendance data inputted.
- Maintained legacy metric applications adjusting Fusion Chart configurations in XML, styling and incorrect data calculations, as well as refactoring code for better performance and readability.

Aug 2014 -Mar 2015

#### **Programmer Analyst**

Lockheed Martin ADIS Team

- Designed flexible database architecture following third normal form design to reduce data size cost.
- Developed intuitive application screens in Panther for financial charge numbers performing database locking operations to prevent parallel manipulation.
- Developed multiple screens in Panther and SQL for Automated
   Depot Integrated System for charge number approval process requiring
   creating new table structures using DDL and DML commands; such as,
   CREATE, ALTER, INSERT, UPDATE and SELECT.

# **Projects**

Jan 2017 present

#### **Artropy**

Personal (Progressive Web Application)

- Developing in Angular, TypeScript, .NET Core, CosmosDB using the Azure cloud platform for infrastructure and Visual Studio Team Services for continuous integration and testing with node package manager for dependency installations and management.
- Using GIT for software change management, peer review and deployment.
- Using **CSS3 Flexbox** for responsive design layout to be user friendly on all platforms; such as , desktop, tablets and mobile.

Jun 2017 - present

#### Portfolio

Personal (Progressive Web Application)

- Developing in Polymer 2.0, Express, CosmosDB and Azure to fully keep track of previous technology exposure and professional reference.
- Deployed using **Azure** continuous integration tools with **GitHub** and managed dependencies using **bower** dependency manager.
- Implemented **Service Worker** to allow cross platform installation; such as, iOS, Android and Windows for native like application interaction.

# **Education**

May 2010 -Aug 2014

### **University of Central Florida**

**B.S in Computer Science**